Naitik Sharma

+91~7003278402 | devnaitik104@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/naitik-sharma | github.com/shutter-codes

Profile Summary

A proficient software developer with 1 year of internship experience and 2 years of freelancing in Java, JavaScript, and its frameworks like react js, next js, node js. Demonstrated expertise in application development and integration at Paytm, Helpy Moto, and Webknot Technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Primary: Javascript, Typescript, React js Next js, Express js ,Node js, PHP, Linux , Java, SpringBoot Additional : MySQL, MongoDB, Kafka, Redis, RabbitMQ, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Github, Linux, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, RestAPI

Core Competencies

Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Data Structures and Algorithms (DSA), Object Oriented Programing (OOP), Debugging, Restful API, Test Driven Development (TDD), Microservice design

Soft skills: Problem-solving, detail-oriented, critical thinking, collaborative, team player, leadership, innovative, reliable

WORK EXPERIENCE

SDE Intern

Jan 2024 – Apr 2024

Paytm, One 97 Communication Private Limited

 $Noida,\ India$

- Developed REST API's for a web based applications using **React and Node js technology** for the IT Asset Management (ITAM) project
- Worked on the backend development of the IPay project, utilizing Java, Spring Boot, Redis, Kafka, MySQL and migrate the data and contributed in the API documentation and wrote test cases of the 8 microservices.

Full stack Developer Intern

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023

Helpy Moto (startup)

Delhi, India

- implemented new features and enhancements to existing applications, resulting in enhancement of **performance** by 5 times and increased customer satisfaction.
- Designed and developed various algorithms for Location hashing and real time provider finding applications like Ola/Uber.

Software Developer, Intern

May 2022 - Oct 2022

Webknot Technologies (startup)

Remote

- Integrated third-party API's to extend application functionality and provide seamless user experiences, adhering to security and data privacy standards
- Utilized a range of technologies, including Flutter, React js, Typescript and Python, to build the application.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

 $\textbf{Unibites (Own StartUP Project)} \mid \textit{React.js} \ , \ \textit{Node.js} \ , \ \textit{Express.js} \ , \ \textit{MongoDB} \ , \ \textit{Git}, \ \textit{Figma}$

Live Link

- Crafted Unibites dashboards for tenants, owners, and admins, streamlining bookings, properties, and accounts.
- Conducted user research, implemented role-based access control, and followed Agile methodology to develop Unibites effectively.
- Operated the project live locally, earning INR 25,000 in three months before selling it for INR 30,000.

Bharat Bank Backend | Java ,spring boot , maven ,spring mvc

Github Link

• Implemented a comprehensive set of banking features, including account management, funds transfers, deposits, withdrawals, and mobile banking, showcasing a deep understanding of financial systems and user requirements.

EDUCATION

Arya College of Engineering and IT

Jaipur, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering [cgpa - 8.53]

Aug. 2020 - May 2024

ACHIEVEMENTS

Prepsat Hiring Jobathon 2023 - Ranked 474 out of 90678 Ninja Hire 2.0 - Ranked 154th and Scored 288/340 RHCSA Certified - Certificate Id: 230-087-397